<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Privacy on PrintN</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Privacy on PrintN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Surveillance Cameras</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/avoiding-surveillance-cameras/2024-09-16-avoiding-surveillance-cameras/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/avoiding-surveillance-cameras/2024-09-16-avoiding-surveillance-cameras/</guid>
      
      <description>Why Might You Want to Avoid Surveillance Cameras? Surveillance cameras are increasingly present in public and private spaces. While their purpose is often linked to safety and security, many people have valid concerns about being constantly monitored. Here are some common motivations for avoiding these cameras:
Activists and Protesters: Individuals advocating for social or political change often wish to protect their identities from authorities or opposing groups. They fear that being identified on camera could lead to harassment, retaliation, or suppression of their efforts.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should You Be Using A VPN?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/should-you-be-using-vpns/2024-09-13-should-you-be-using-a-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/should-you-be-using-vpns/2024-09-13-should-you-be-using-a-vpn/</guid>
      
      <description>Have you ever seen those ads promising that using a VPN will keep you safe from hackers and government surveillance? It’s easy to get caught up in the hype, but how much of it is actually true?What Is A VPN? A Virtual Private Network (VPN) is a technology that routes your internet traffic through a remote server, masking your IP address and hiding your online activity from your Internet Service Provider (ISP).</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Privacy Matters.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/your-privacy-matters/2024-09-10-your-privacy-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/your-privacy-matters/2024-09-10-your-privacy-matters/</guid>
      
      <description>Definition of Privacy The terms privacy, security, and anonymity are often confused and used interchangeably, yet they each serve distinct purposes in the digital world:
Privacy: The ability to control what information you share and with whom, ensuring that your personal data and activities remain within your chosen boundaries. Security: The protection of your information and digital assets against potential threats or harm, such as hacking or unauthorized access. Anonymity: The ability to act online without revealing your identity, allowing you to engage in activities without being personally identified.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
